Guide to the Rosemary Trump Papers, 1950-2005 AIS.2005.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Political Activism, 1982-2004; III.
  - National, 1.
    - Political Planning Retreat, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Presidential Election- General, 2000, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
    - Presidential Election- Newspaper Clippings and Leaflets, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Presidential Election- SEIU and AFL-CIO Materials, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Presidential Election- Women, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Pennsylvania, 2.
    - Election Materials, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Electoral College-General, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Electoral College-Proceedings, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Gubernatorial Inauguration, 1991, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 9-10)
    - Pennsylvania Democratic Party, 1996-2004 (Box 17, Folder 11-14)
    - Pennsylvania Federation of Democratic Women, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 2001-2002 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Presidential Visits, 1993-1997 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Regional Elections Material, 1999-2000 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Westmoreland County Democratic Party, Candidacy for Chair, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Westmoreland County Democratic Party, General Files, 2001-2004 (Box 17, Folder 20-22)
    - Westmoreland County Democratic Party, Meeting Materials, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Westmoreland County Democratic Party, Member Lists, 1998-2002 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Westmoreland County Democratic Party, New Democratic Voice, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Westmoreland County Democratic Party, Spring Banquet, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Westmoreland County Democratic Party, Survey, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 27)
- Community Activism, 1982-2005; IV.
  Series IV contains files from active community organizations in the Pittsburgh area. The files are arranged alphabetically by organization name or subject and include newspaper clippings, newsletters, correspondence, reports and meeting minutes. The public television files date from the 1990s and detail the sale of Pittsburgh public television channel 16 (WQEX), which Trump and others opposed.
  - Awards Dinners, 1985-2004 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Citizens Budget Campaign of South West Pennsylvania, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Citizens League of South Western Pennsylvania- Correspondence, 1989, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
  - Citizens League of South Western Pennsylvania- Forum, 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Citizens League of South Western Pennsylvania- General, 1988-1992 (Box 18, Folder 6-9)
  - Citizens League of South Western Pennsylvania- Minutes, 1989, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 10-11)
  - Citizens League of South Western Pennsylvania- Pamphlets and Articles, 1988-1991 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Federal Judge Selection Committee- Correspondence, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Federal Judge Selection Committee- Procedures, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Greater Westmoreland County Labor Council, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Junior Achievement, 1987-1989 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Just Harvest, 1992-2004 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Labor Articles, 1997-2005 (Box 18, Folder 18-19)
  - Mon Valley Initiative, 1989-2000 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Peace Links, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Pennsylvania Economy League, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 22-23)
  - Pittsburgh Area Miscellaneous, 1982-2004 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Pittsburgh Building Owners Welfare Fund, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Privatization of Public Sector, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Public Television- ACLC Media Committee, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
  - Public Television- Citizens for Independent Public Broadcasting, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Public Television- Correspondence, 1990-2001 (Box 19, Folder 7-11)
  - Public Television- Emails, 2000-2002 (Box 19, Folder 12-13)
  - Public Television- Legal Action, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Public Television- Miscellaneous, 1990s (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Public Television- Newspaper Articles, no date (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Public Television- Proposals and Resolutions, 1990s (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Public Television- Publicity, no date (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Thomas Merton Center - New People, 1998-2004 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Three Rivers Community Fund, 2000-2004 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Three Rivers Labor Management Committee, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - United Way, 2000-2003 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Working Together Consortium, 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 23)
- Labor History Preservation, 1976-2004; V.
  Series V contains materials that stem from Rosemary Trump's interest in preserving labor history. The series is divided into two subseries: Steel Heritage of Southwest Pennsylvania and Other Labor History.
  - Steel Heritage of Southwestern Pennsylvania, 1987-2004; 1.
    Subseries I. is arranged alphabetically and dates from 1987-2004. It mostly contains the records of non-profit organizations aimed at reinvigorating interest in Southwest Pennsylvania's steel heritage and preserving its historical landmarks. This material provides insight into several significant events such the Homestead Strike Centennial in 1992, development of the Rivers of Steel Heritage Area and preservation of the Bost Building (Homestead, PA) and Carrie Furnaces (Braddock, PA).
    - Battle of Homestead Foundation- Board Member Materials, 1997-2002 (Box 20, Folder 1-5)
    - Battle of Homestead Foundation- Miscellaneous, 1995-2002 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Battle of Homestead Foundation- Pump House Commemoration, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Battle of Homestead Foundation- Pump House Development Plans, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Battle of Homestead News, 2000-2002 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Bost Building- Architectural Qualifications, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 10-11)
    - Bost Building- Condition, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Bost Building- Costs of Renovation, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Bost Building- Purchase, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Bost Building- Renovation, 1990, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 15-16)
    - Centennial Celebration, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Homestead Centennial Committee, 1989-1992 (Box 20, Folder 18-21)
    - Interpreting the Pump House, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Leaflets and Articles, 1992-2002 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - National Historic Landmark Nomination, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - National Park Service - Special Resource Study, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1989-1999 (Box 20, Folder 26-27)
    - Projects, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - The River Ran Red, 1991-1992 (Box 21, Folder 2-3)
    - Rivers of Steel Heritage Grant Applications, 1999-2004 (Box 21, Folder 4-7)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Board Member Materials, 1992-2004 (Box 21, Folder 8-22)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Bylaws and Articles of Incorporation, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Capital Campaign, 2001-2002 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Concept Plan, Draft, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Concept Plan, Final, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Education and Events, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Financial Statements, 1992-2003 (Box 22, Folder 4-8)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Implementation Application, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Legal Matters, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Living Legacy of Steel in Southwest Pennsylvania, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Management Action Plan, Delaware and Lehigh Canal, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Management Action Plan, Rivers of Steel, 1993, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 13-14)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Miscellaneous, 1996-2000 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Newspaper Clippings, 1990s (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Pennsylvania Heritage Parks Program, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Press Materials, 1992-2002 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Promotion, 1996-2002 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Rivers of Steel Heritage Area, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Steel Heritage Chronicle, 1992-2002 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Steel Heritage Corporation- Taskforce, 1988, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 22-23)
  - Other Labor History, 1976-2004; 2.
    Subseries II. documents the efforts of several non-profit organizations to preserve labor history both locally and nationally. The most extensive files are from the Pennsylvania Labor History Society (PLHS). These files describe actions taken at PLHS meetings and conferences, as well as projects paying tribute to labor activists like Fannie Sellins and Monsignor Charles Owen Rice.
    - Alliance of National Heritage Areas - International Conference, Guidebook, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Alliance of National Heritage Areas - International Conference, Handouts, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Labor's Heritage, 1994-1997 (Box 23, Folder 3-5)
    - PA Center for Labor Relations- General, 1989-1990 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - PA Center for Labor Relations- Symposium, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - PA Labor History Society- Conference, 2003-2004 (Box 23, Folder 8-9)
    - PA Labor History Society- Fannie Sellins Memorial, 1989-1997 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - PA Labor History Society- General, 1976-2002 (Box 23, Folder 11-18)
    - PA Labor History Society- Charles Owen Rice, 1993-1998 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - PA Labor History Society- Publications, 1976-2003 (Box 23, Folder 20-22)
    - Philip Murray Institute of Labor Studies- General, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Philip Murray Institute of Labor Studies- Labor Outreach, 1990-1991 (Box 23, Folder 24)
- Labor and Religion, 1992-2004; VI.
  Series VI describes cooperative efforts between clergy and labor leaders to promote better economic conditions for workers in the Pittsburgh region. The general files contain correspondence and leaflets, which focus primarily on establishing a living wage and secondarily on prospects for peace in the Middle East.
  - Comments, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - General Files, 1982-2004 (Box 24, Folder 2-9)
  - National Interfaith Committee for Worker Justice, 2003 (Box 24, Folder 10-11)
  - Religion and Labor Council of Western PA, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 12)
- Advocacy for Women, 1978-2004; VII.
  Series VII dates from 1978-2004 and is arranged alphabetically. It includes research files on the situation of working women and the Equal Rights Amendment. Additional files contain materials from organizations created by women to improve their situation such as "9 to 5", Coalition of Labor Union Women and National Organization for Women.
  - 9 to 5- General, 1981-1982 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - 9 to 5- History, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - 9 to 5- Newsletters, 1979-1991 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women: Convention, 1982-1991 (Box 25, Folder 4-7)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women: General, 1981-1982 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Coalition of Labor Union Women: Newsletters, 1980-1991 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - ERA, 1978-1981 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - General Files, 1980-1988 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - National Organization for Women: Miscellaneous, 1981-1993 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - National Organization for Women: National Newsletters, 1980-1984 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - National Organization for Women: Pennsylvania Newsletters, 1980-1986 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - National Organization for Women: Pittsburgh Newsletters, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Pittsburgh Working Women, 1981-1982 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Reports, 1982-1994 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Women's Advisory Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Women's Leadership Programs, 1991-1992 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Women's Political Caucus: General, 1980-1983 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Women's Political Caucus: Newsletters, 1980-1984 (Box 25, Folder 21)